jaisiyaram.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy

This site complies with the following Privacy Policy. By using this site, you indicate your acceptance of Jaisiyaram.com’s Online Privacy Policy. Shree Bindu Sewa Sansthan (India) and Swami Balendu e.V. (Germany) are non-profit charitable organizations. All donations made are free of tax and thus fully support these charitable organizations.

The Jaisiyaram Trading Company is our partner company and all profits made are donated to Shree Bindu Sewa Sansthan for the support of their charity projects.

Privacy policy

  1. Introduction

1.1    We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website ([www.jaisiyaram.com](http://www.jaisiyaram.com/)) visitors and service users.

1.2    This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

1.3    We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

1.4    In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to Shree Bindu Sewa Sansthan.[ For more information about us, see Section 13.]

  2. Credit

2.1    This document was created using a template from SEQ Legal ([https://seqlegal.com](https://seqlegal.com/)).

  3. How we use your personal data

3.1    In this Section 3 we have set out:

(a)    the general categories of personal data that we may process;

(b)    [in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data];

(c)    the purposes for which we may process personal data; and

(d)    the legal bases of the processing.

3.2    We may process data about your use of our website and services (" **usage data** "). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services, however is not linked to any person or profiling. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

3.3    We may process your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our services (" **service data** "). The service data may include your name, address, phone number, email address and data relevant to our offered services. The source of the service data is you. The service data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.

3.4    We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services or charity projects (" **enquiry data** "). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent.

3.5    We may process information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information (" **customer relationship data** "). The customer relationship data may include your name, your job title or role, your contact details, and information contained in communications between us and you. The source of the customer relationship data is you. The customer relationship data may be processed for the purposes of managing our relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of those communications and promoting our products and services to customers. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper management of our customer relationships.

3.6    We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (" **notification data** "). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.

3.7    We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (" **correspondence data** "). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.

3.8    We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

3.9    In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 3, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

  4. Providing your personal data to others

4.1    We generally only use your personal data within our company and trust. If third parties are involved for data handling, we will only provide data in the amount that is necessary for having said services fulfilled and have a binding contract that will ensure that the GDPR laws are fulfilled.

4.2    In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

  5. International transfers of your personal data

5.1    In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Union.

5.2    The hosting facilities for our website are situated in the USA. The server provider self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield, as administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. These frameworks were created to enable companies to comply with data protection requirements when transferring personal information from the EEA and Switzerland to the United States. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Frameworks, the Privacy Shield Frameworks shall govern.

  6. Retaining and deleting personal data

6.1    This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

6.2    Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

6.3    Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

  7. Amendments

7.1    We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

7.2    You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

  8. Your rights

8.1    In this Section 8, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

8.2    Your principal rights under data protection law are:

(a)    the right to access;

(b)    the right to rectification;

(c)    the right to erasure;

(d)    the right to restrict processing;

(e)    the right to object to processing;

(f)     the right to data portability;

(g)    the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and

(h)    the right to withdraw consent.

8.3    You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.

8.4    You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

8.5    In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

8.6    In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

8.7    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

8.8    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

8.9    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

8.10  To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

(a)    consent; or

(b)    that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,

        and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

8.11  If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

8.12  To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

8.13  You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us.

  9. About cookies

9.1    A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

9.2    Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

9.3    Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

  10. Cookies that we use

10.1  Most of our used cookies are so-called ‘Session Cookies’ which are automatically deleted are terminating the visit of our website. Others are stored on your device until deleted. These cookies make it possible for our website to recognize you on your next visit. This can be prevented with the proper settings in your browser, which can also notify you about any cookies placed and only allow cookies in cases determined by you or activate the deletion of cookies on each closing of browser windows. The deactivation of cookies can interfere with the seamless use of this website. Any cookies used are done on consent and with legal right to do so according to the GDPR.

  11. Cookies used by our service providers

11.1  Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

11.2  We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

        Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

        This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users' IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out. Privacy Shield participant

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application. The interaction and information obtained through this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.

11.3 This website uses Facebook Like buttons and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.) This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it. The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant. You can find further information under <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>   
If you are connected to facebook during your visit of our website, information is connected and likes or shares are transferred to Facebook Inc.

11.4  This website uses Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google Inc.) The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant. <https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy>.

11.5 This website uses LinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation) The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>

11.6  This website uses Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.) The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant. <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>

11.7  This website uses StumbleUpon button and social widgets (StumbleUpon, Inc.) The StumbleUpon button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the StumbleUpon social network provided by StumbleUpon, Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. <https://www.redditinc.com/policies/privacy-policy>

11.8  This website uses Reddit button and widgets (reddit inc.) The reddit button and widgets are services allowing interaction with the reddit platform provided by reddit inc. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. <http://www.stumbleupon.com/privacy>

11.9  This website uses the YouTube widget. YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages. Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy. Privacy Shield participant. [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=it](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=it)

11.10 Donation Payment Provider: Paypal By registering or authenticating, Users allow this Application to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, this Application will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.  
Log In with PayPal (PayPal Inc.) Log In with PayPal is a registration and authentication service provided by PayPal Inc. and is connected to the PayPal network. Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing: See the PayPal privacy policy – Privacy Policy. <https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>

12.1  Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a)    [https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en) (Chrome);

(b)    [https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences) (Firefox);

(c)    [http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/](http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/) (Opera);

(d)    [https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies) (Internet Explorer);

(e)    [https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411) (Safari); and

(f)     [https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy) (Edge).

12.2  Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

12.3  If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

  13. Our details

13.1  This website is owned and operated by Shree Bindu Sewa Sansthan.

13.2  We are registered in India, Uttar Pradesh as a registered charitable trust at Parikrama Marg, Ram Nagar, Vrindavan, 281121.

13.3  You can contact us:

(a)    by post, to the postal address given above;

(b)    using our website contact form;

(c)    by telephone, on 0091 9997710000; or

(d)    by email, using info@jaisiyaram.com.

Our sites collect no personally identifying information about individuals except when specifically and knowingly provided by such individuals. We do record information such as time of day, browser type, browser language, and IP address when you interact with the site. Jaisiyaram.com uses this information to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. We also use this information to verify the number of discrete times you visit this web site each day.

We collect the e-mail addresses of those who subscribe to our newsletter, request any service and order our products. By filling a form on Jaisiyaram.com the subscriber agrees on receiving emails from Jaisiyaram.com. The subscriber's data is stored in our secured server and protected with up to 256-bit Secure Sockets Layer encryption. Jaisiyaram.com will contact the subscribers with mails regarding the requested service and order and promotional mails for programs and charity projects. The provided information is kept confidential and is not shared with or sold to any other company or organization. By filling any form on the JAISIYARAM.COM website in order to attend any of the programs, to invite for programs or to use any service, paid or free (for example distance healing), you give JAISIYARAM.COM the permission to display your picture, location and name which was provided on our website and across the internet. By filling a form you agree and confirm that you do not have an objection to this display. Following our privacy policy, your email address will not be shared or displayed in any case. If you do not want this, you are always free to unsubscribe or to ask us at [info@jaisiyaram.com](mailto:info@jaisiyaram.com) to remove you from our list of using our services. All emails contain an [unsubscribe link](http://www.jaisiyaram.com/unsubscribe.htm) which can be used to opt-out or you [click here to unsubscribe](http://www.jaisiyaram.com/unsubscribe.htm). It is an automated system and the email-address will be removed from the program and the subscription list within seconds.

While we will seek to require third parties with whom we have agreements to follow appropriate privacy policies, we do not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of third parties. Our web site contains links, including e-commerce opportunities with affiliates, partners and associates, to other sites that are not maintained by us. If you visit these sites, please look for their privacy policy.

We can be reached via email at [info@jaisiyaram.com](mailto:info@jaisiyaram.com).
